

Akshay Kachroo

Date of birth: 28/11/1994 | **Phone number:** (+91) 9711138632 (Mobile) | **Email address:**

akshaykachroo2050@gmail.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/akshay-kachroo/

ABOUT ME

Data Scientist with 6 years of relevant experience in IT - Al ML Analytics, keenly interested in Data Science and Machine Learning. Well-versed in numerous programming languages and tools with strong expertise in Python, PL/SQL, and R.

WORK EXPERIENCE

28/06/2021 - CURRENT Gurgaon, India

DATA SCIENTIST ACCENTURE INDIA PVT LTD

- Formulating, suggesting, and managing data-driven projects, aimed at furthering the business interests.
- Ensuring proper alignment of analytics with strategic business initiatives encompassing understanding of omnichannel behavior, building recommendation engines, and store viability model.
- Managing full development cycle of planning, analysis, design, and development.
- Working as an ML Engineer on the MLOps platform, whereby designing the end-to-end ML pipeline for client solutions.
- Providing optimized business solutions to top-performing European and US Finance and Healthcare clients.
- Using NLP to perform text sentiment analytics and summarize the results on Qlikview.
- Using ML Algorithms like Text analytics, Clustering, Time series analysis, Regression, and Gradient Boosting to build robust models.
- Building robust dashboards for certain models like COE and Market Mix Models.
- Providing advanced analytical solutions to clients from across the globe in multiple domains.
- Automating the Industrialized CI/CD ML Pipeline on the client's AWS platform.
- Engagement in the validation of the Test and UAT pipeline using Docker and Kubernetes.

My main achievement:

Making the pipeline furthermore optimized by reducing the execution time by 25%. Making the whole ML pipeline industrialized for all future products as well.

13/06/2020 - 25/06/2021 Gurgaon, India

DECISION SCIENTIST AXTRIA INDIA PVT LTD

- Understanding the US Fintech and Healthcare-based Bigdata and through ETL analysis and dashboards, providing/reporting data stories to the clients to help them take better business decisions.
- Handling end-to-end data analytics pipeline to provide solutions to business problems.
- Using languages like Python, R, and Pyspark to perform the analysis and undergo the forecasting.
- Building robust dashboards for certain models like COE and Market Mix Models.
- · Using ML Algorithms like Text analytics, Clustering, Time series analysis, and Regression to build robust models.

My main achievement:

Making the dashboard and entire ETL reporting automated so as to increase productivity and available bandwidth for other tasks.

Making the ETL dashboard parameterized thereby making it reusable for future purposes.

19/03/2018 - 10/06/2020 Indore, India

SYSTEM ENGINEER TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

- Managing and visualizing the data using ETL-based analytics tools for BFSI and Energy & Resource domain projects.
- Handling the fixes and bugs of the Python application and validating with Docker and Kubernetes.
- Handling the server-side (database, jobs, procedures, batch & application severs) of the client industry with good exposure to shell-scripting.
- Engaging in Deployment and patching activity and providing technical solutions to Clients within a pre-defined SLA.

My main achievement:

Designing the detailed technical documentation for future resources such that production work never gets affected. Resolving the core code issue thereby making the production TAT faster.

09/09/2017 - 17/03/2018 Delhi, India

GIS ANALYST CE INFO SYSTEMS PVT LTD

- Retrieved data using SQL to resolve client difficulties and investigated the data mismatch & corrected it.
- · Generated workarounds for many sorts of application difficulties using SQL and UNIX Shell Scripts.

- Guided clients through troubleshooting techniques to fix typical software problems.
- Archived data according to SLA which was transferred to Hadoop servers and stored in Hive tables for analytic purposes.
- Accomplished day-to-day tasks and executed the project application maintenance, as well as PL/SQL packages, triggers, dB linkages, and schedulers.
- Managed the Geographical data using GIS tool, MySQL and providing navigational solutions to the client.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/03/2013 - 29/04/2017 Delhi, India

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY ELECTRONICS University of Delhi

Address New Delhi, 110096, Delhi, India | Website http://mac.du.ac.in/ | Field of study Electronics and automation

DIGITAL SKILLS

Machine Learning | Programming languages (Python and R program) | SQL (MySQL) | Qlik sense | Lisp, MPI, Octave, PostgreSQL, Spark, PySpark, Pandas, Keras | AWS Web Services | GIT Hub | Data Science, Data Analytics, Data Visualization | Natural language processing | CI/CD (Gitlab CI) | Devops | MLOps

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PROJECTS

Donors choose prediction Objective: Implementation of predictive model using the donor's choose dataset to predict the number of projects which will be approved in respect to the total submitted ones.

ML Algorithms used: EDA using Python, correlation determination, NLP, Gridsearch CV.

Link github.com/kachrooakshay95

Prediction of Food delivery time Objective: Building an end-to-end model to predict the time taken by restaurant in delivering the post after placement of online order.

ML Algorithms used: EDA using Python, correlation determination, Gridsearch CV, Logistics Regression, Ensemble, Random Forest, Decision Trees.

Link github.com/kachrooakshay95

HONOURS AND AWARDS

09/2022

STAR AWARD - Accenture Pvt Ltd • Awarded the STAR AWARD for leading with innovation.

12/2020

BRAVO AWARD - Axtria India Pvt Ltd • Awarded the BRAVO AWARD for lasting impact and great contribution to the team at Axtria.

2019

Analytics Vidhya • Publisher recognition by ANALYTICS VIDHYA for my article on Medium which was based on Predicting Food Delivery TimeHackathon.

Link medium.com/@akshaykachroo2050